Sahil Jadhav

Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

SUMMARY

Location: Mumbai, Maharashtra, India Email: sahilj5645@gmail.com | Mobile: 8104081285

Dedicated Software Developer specializing in full-stack web application with proficiency in the MERN stack and Dot Net. Skilled in writing clean, optimized code to enhance web application performance and integrating features such as Chat functionality, Email Integration, WebSocket, and Geolocation. Experienced with Databases, REST APIs, and MVC frameworks. Actively engaged in continuous learning to expand and refine my skill set.

SKILLS

Languages : JavaScript ES6, C Sharp, HTML5, CSS3
Frameworks : React.js, Angular, Express, Node.js,.NET

ORM : Dapper, Entity Framework

Libraries : Material, Redux, React Router, Socket.io, Nodemailer, Linq, Kendo

Databases : MongoDB,SQL Server, MySql

Dev Tools : Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, Postman, SSMS, Git, GitHub

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Jul 2024 – present

General Diagnostics International PVT LTD

- Developed web interfaces using HTML, CSS, and Kendo UI for responsive and user-friendly applications.
- Implemented repository services design pattern within an MVC architecture
- Utilized Entity Framework with DbContext for efficient database interaction, Worked extensively with the laboratory machines' database and created Web APIs for seamless data communication and to support mobile applications.
- Implemented automated email and WhatsApp notifications to users.

Software Developer Intern

Dec 2023 - June 2024

Systenics Solutions

- Built responsive web interfaces with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Angular, including mobile apps using Angular and Ionic for enhanced user experience.
- Designed relational schemas and managed databases using SQL and ORM frameworks, developing modular MVC architecture with custom BLL and DLL layers. Developed APIs in .NET for seamless mobile application integration.

React Frontend Developer Intern

Sept 2023 - Nov 2023

Creto Technologia PVT LTD

- Developed reusable React components with efficient use of hooks for data flow, implemented API calls with shimmer UI for loading states, managed state with Redux, and handled routing with React Router.
- Enabled real-time chat using WebSocket. Enhanced and developed APIs using Node.js to showcase website features, bid placements and gig management, with JWT-based user authentication to ensure secure access.

EDUCATION

University of Mumbai

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology

CGPA:-9.40

PROJECTS

Admin Dashboard

<u>Technology Used</u>:- HTML, CSS,Material UI, React JS, Node.js, Express.js, Mongo DB

- a comprehensive admin dashboard for managing customer data, admin profiles, products, transactions, and sales overview, with an interactive geolocation feature for visualizing user distribution.
- Utilized Nivo for data visualization, created API endpoints using createApi and fetchBaseQuery from Redux Toolkit, and integrated Material UI for icons and widgets.

Momento Technology Used:- HTML, CSS, Material UI, React JS, Node. js, Express. js, Mongo DB

- A Social Media Application Developed a platform for users to connect, share moments with photos, and engage in real-time chat using Socket.io.
- Utilized Multer for photo storage, managed state with Redux, and enhanced UI with Material UI icons and widgets.

Job Posting Platform

Technology Used:- Node.js, Express.js, Mongo DB

- Developed secure registration, login endpoints for companies, implemented email verification using OTP, and utilized JWT for secure authentication and authorization.
- Created endpoints for companies to post job listings and Automated email notifications to candidates with Nodemailer about job postings. Used MongoDB for storing company details, job postings, and email logs